Othneil Drew - Senior Software Engineer

"Drew continues to astound me with how quickly he can learn and apply new skills."

- Captain Roscoe Edwards (Manager)

(678) 912-7177 othneild@gmail.com www.othneildrew.com linkedin.com/in/othneildrew

Cypress, TX

Private Pilot turned UI/UX expert and pro Googler with 10+ years of diverse leadership experience. Skilled in product lifecycle management, known for creativity, strengthening client relations, and successfully leading high-performing teams. Eager learner dedicated to improving lifes through innovation.

Technical Skills:

- Languages: Typescript, JavaScript (including Node.js, ES13+), PHP, SQL, Python, HTML5, SASS/SCSS, LESS
- Frameworks & Libraries: NextJS, React, React Native, Redux, RTK Query, Electron, Tauri, Express, Laravel, HTMX, Tailwind, Bulma CSS, Sequelize, PIXI.JS, CesiumJS, JQuery, Semantic UI, Bootstrap, jscodeshift
- UI/UX: Figma, Affinity Designer, GIMP, Photoshop, Mogups, User stories, Wireframes & Prototyping
- Tools: Git, NPM, Webpack, Babel, Gulp, MySQL, Unit/Integration testing, codemods
- Technologies: MongoDB, Redis, Async/Await, Promises, AWS, Linux, Nginx, Apache, WordPress
- Comm: HTTP/S, UDP, TCP/IP (Sockets), FTP, WebRTC, Redis, REST, AJAX, JSON/XML, SSH, Serial, I2C
- Embedded Systems & IoT: Raspberry Pi, Arduino, ESP32/8266
- Other: SEO, Canvas, Microservices, MVC, SCRUM/Agile/Kanban, JIra, Git (Git-Flow), CI/CD & Code Automation, Data scraping, Database Design & Normalization, ITAR & 508 Compliance

"Othneil is extremely creative and technologically savvy. He enjoys learning..." - R. Yancy (Professor)

Experience

Senior Software Engineer, Front End (Team Lead) | Secberus, Remote

NOV 2021 - PRESENT

Improve companies' cloud security infrastructure through configuration governance.

- Plan app releases; executing deployments across develop, staging, and production environments.
- Facilitate inter-team communication, improve team workflow with Kanban and streamlined PR reviews.
- Implement advance codemods and automation, which improved project maintainability through refactoring over 11,000 lines of code while increasing release frequency to weekly from once per month.

Senior Full Stack Developer (Web Lead) | Snaju Development, Houston, TX JUN 2019 - NOV 2021

Build high-quality enterprise software ranging from avionics command/control systems to websites and IoT.

- Led discussions and client discovery meetings to establish goals, tech requirements and budget.
- Deployed and manage cross-platform apps (React Native, Electron) using various dev-op pipelines.
- Integrate with third-party services, APIs, and Linux-based microprocessors/controllers using various communication protocols.

Entrepreneur & Software Engineer | Student Pilot Portal, Houston, TX

MAY 2015 - PRESENT

A passion project to help pilots to learn to fly more effectively. Based on NextJS and microservices.

- Write custom React hooks and HOCs to relay real-time data using sockets and events.
- Implement project features in multiple languages using Agile/Scrum methodology.
- Use Node/Python to process and aggregate large datasets to create REST APIs.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Aviation Science Management | Texas Southern University

STEM Scholarship(3), Coursework: C++

TBA (1 class remaining)

[Othneil] can be depended upon at a moment's notice... very efficient with managing his time between community affairs, his education, work, and hobbies. I eagerly recommend [him] for any endeavor that he pursues..." - Cenita Heywood (Manager)